BASILLE FELIZ SIMPLICIO

SUMMARY

Hello, you can call me "Bash" (not the shell).

I have a passion for quality assurance (QA) engineering, with over 10 years of experience in the tech industry. However, my skills extend beyond being a QA Engineer alone. Throughout my career, I have also worked as a Software Developer and a Business Analyst for the companies I have been employed with.

SKILLS

TESTING

Manual Testing, Functional Testing, A/B Testing, Test Automation, Cypress, Selenium

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Python, Django Framework, React, Git

PROJECT MANAGEMENT TOOL

JIRA, Asana, Trello

WEBSITES

Portfolio: https://bashsimplicio.github.io/
Github Link: https://github.com/bashsimplicio

EXPERIENCE

Experience Digital, Remote — QA Engineer / Business Analyst

May 2022 - PRESENT

Responsible for testing web and mobile applications from different clients. My responsibilities include creating test plans and automated tests using Cypress for different projects I am assigned to.

As Business Analyst, we study business workflows and create user stories based on their requirements.

Spiralyze, Remote — *QA Engineer*

October 2018 - April 2022

Responsible for testing websites from different clients through A/B testing. I served as a Senior Tester. I take on the QA Lead role when my superior is not available. My responsibilities include assigning QA tasks to

Junior testers and doing the final QA before forwarding it to the Project Manager.

Ingenuity Global Consulting, Davao City, PH — QA Engineer

May 2013 - June 2020

I was assigned to multiple projects involved in understanding the requirements, conducting web or mobile application tests using different test scenarios on browsers, documenting issues found, and creating bug reports or tickets including detailed steps to reproduce, actual output, and expected results.

I was the main QA in an internal ERP project using the Odoo framework and created user documentation through Sphinx. Performed running of scripts provided by the developers and executed tests using the subversion repository. Most of the projects I worked on used Agile methodology

I was also a Software Developer for a limited time on an internal project to track record updates from team members per project that was sent to clients via email on a regular basis.

EDUCATION

University of the Philippines Mindanao, Davao City, PH — Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

June 2008 - April 2013

OTHERS

I was one of the trainers of a two-day workshop for Capability Training for CM-ACTS System Development and Maintenance on October 8-9 2022.

During the training, I shared the best QA practices I learned throughout my years as a QA.